<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>🚀 Kamil Wiecek</title>
        <description>I am building in public my first product, sharing the journey, challenges, and progress along the way to inspire and connect with others.</description>
        <link>/</link>
        <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 16:13:26 +0200</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 16:13:26 +0200</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Jekyll v3.9.5</generator>
        
            <item>
                <title>How I’ll choose what product to build</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ll divide the process into two main stages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;creating-a-list-of-ideas-and-initial-selection&quot;&gt;Creating a list of ideas and initial selection&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the recommendation from Peter Levels’ book Make, I’ll focus on problems I’ve personally encountered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first step, I’ll create a rough list of problems and potential product ideas that come to mind. Then I’ll narrow it down to a maximum of three ideas for deeper analysis. The goal is to find something that solves a real problem and has a chance of actually being useful to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I’ll describe these products on my blog and ask for feedback in places where I can find potential users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/02-choosing-product-common-what-i-d-like-and-what-somoene-would-pay.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Overlap between &apos;What I would like to build&apos; and &apos;What someone would pay for&apos; — highlighting the sweet spot as potential product to build&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;describing-the-three-selected-product-ideas&quot;&gt;Describing the Three Selected Product Ideas&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each product description will include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name and Description&lt;/strong&gt; – A short summary of the product and the problem it solves. I’ll explain why the problem is important and how solving it could help people.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Target Audience&lt;/strong&gt; – Who will benefit the most from this product.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Competition and Differentiation&lt;/strong&gt; – What similar solutions already exist and how my product will be different or better.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Business Model&lt;/strong&gt; – How I plan to make money from this product and what costs I expect.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marketing Ideas&lt;/strong&gt; – How I could get people interested in the product.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concerns and Challenges&lt;/strong&gt; – What I’m worried about and what might be hard during the process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;main-goal-for-may-2025&quot;&gt;Main Goal for May 2025&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal for this month is to clearly describe these ideas using the structure above and define what I can quickly build to test market interest — a scope of work for an MVP. It’s important to check as early as possible if the market really needs the solution, before I invest more time and resources into it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
                <link>/blog/how-will-i-choose-product-to-build</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/how-will-i-choose-product-to-build</guid>
                
                <category>choosing product to build</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Why am I going to build a product?</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The list will be sharp and to the point, without any filler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’ll have full decision-making power over what I do and how I do it&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I enjoy pursuing goals I set for myself. After completing a demanding AI course and an algotrading bot project, I’m looking for a new, bigger challenge.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My favorite part of professional work is designing and building systems.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is one of two paths I’ve been considering for years. It seems less risky than the other one—building my own service-based company.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ve always had a few product ideas in mind.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I want to do something beyond working for someone else. The main stage of building my professional career is already behind me.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nothing truly bad will happen if I fail — at worst, I’ll gain valuable experience and learn something.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m inspired by people who have done it, like Troy Hunt and his &lt;a href=&quot;https://haveibeenpwned.com/&quot;&gt;Have I Been Pwned&lt;/a&gt; project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I was inspired by Peter Levels’ book Make, in which he shares his experiences building startups solo.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the future, I’d like to be able to say: “I once built my own product, even though I wasn’t sure it would work out.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’d like to build a personal brand along the lines of “he makes cool stuff.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maybe I’ll even make some money from it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned, this blog entry will also serve as a place I can return to whenever I need a reminder of why I started, especially in moments when motivation runs low.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
                <link>/blog/why-am-i-going-to-build-a-product</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/why-am-i-going-to-build-a-product</guid>
                
                <category>motivation</category>
                
                <category>building product</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>