<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>🚀 Kamil Wiecek</title>
        <description>I am building in public my first product, sharing the journey, challenges, and progress along the way to inspire and connect with others.</description>
        <link>/</link>
        <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 15:55:44 +0200</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 15:55:44 +0200</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Jekyll v3.9.5</generator>
        
            <item>
                <title>✅ How I Delivered the First Planned Milestone and Started Collecting Free Trading Signals</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;-completed-tasks&quot;&gt;✅ Completed Tasks&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✔️ Selected three active signal groups for analysis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✔️ Created Python script for Telegram message fetching&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✔️ Built Go program for signal extraction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✔️ Developed message viewing tool with daily signal display&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/08-print-captures-signal.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot showing the signal extraction program in action, displaying captured trading signals from Telegram groups&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
                <link>/blog/how-i-captured-signals</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/how-i-captured-signals</guid>
                
                <category>signals auditor</category>
                
                <category>building product</category>
                
                <category>product implementation</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>🕵️ How I Selected Signal Groups to Analyze First</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;️-actions-taken&quot;&gt;🛠️ Actions Taken:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;wrote a script that fetches messages from Telegram and puts them into a SQLite database&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;looked for a free signal pattern for each channel on Telegram&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;analyzed, using SQL, how often signals appeared&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the example below you will see the analysis of Crypto Inner Circle®, which allowed me to exclude this group for now because they publish signals too rarely:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/07-sql-query-to-decide-if-proceed-with-crypto-inner-circle.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;How I decide to skip Crypto Inner Circle®&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;finally-after-processing-almost-160k-telegram-messages-decided-to-start-with&quot;&gt;Finally, after processing almost 160k Telegram messages decided to start with:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cryptosignals0rg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;whalepumpgroup23&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;wallstreetqueenofficial&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;️--again-just-to-be-clear--im-not-recommending-any-of-these-groups-or-believing-in-their-effectiveness-in-fact-their-effectiveness-is-the-topic-of-the-product-im-currently-working-on&quot;&gt;⚠️  Again…. Just to be clear – I’m not recommending any of these groups or believing in their effectiveness. In fact, their “effectiveness” is the topic of the product I’m currently working on.&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
                <link>/blog/how-i-selected-first-3-signal-groups</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/how-i-selected-first-3-signal-groups</guid>
                
                <category>signals auditor</category>
                
                <category>building product</category>
                
                <category>product implementation</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>🔍 How I Found Trading Signal Groups to Audit (not for trading)</title>
                <description>&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/06-how-i-found-trading-signals-groups.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;How I Found Trading Signal Groups&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first task I set for myself was to gather a list of signal groups I’d like to audit and choose three to start with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;️-just-to-be-clear--im-not-recommending-any-of-these-groups-or-believing-in-their-effectiveness-in-fact-their-effectiveness-is-the-topic-of-the-product-im-currently-working-on&quot;&gt;⚠️ Just to be clear – I’m not recommending any of these groups or believing in their effectiveness. In fact, their “effectiveness” is the topic of the product I’m currently working on.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;-research-mode-chatgpt--perplexity-in-action&quot;&gt;📚 Research Mode: ChatGPT &amp;amp; Perplexity in Action&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To collect the list of groups, I used LLMs: ChatGPT and Perplexity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Select 20 crypto trading signal sources. Choose the most popular.
Rules:
- ALWAYS consider groups with a large number of members as popular, both free and paid
- For each group, if the information is available:
    - ALWAYS include how the trading signals are delivered (e.g., Telegram group, email, Signal, Discord, website, or something else)
    - If possible, include the price of the signal group
    - If possible, include the number of members in the signal group
    - If possible, find out whether the signals are free, paid, or both
- ALWAYS exclude non-English-speaking groups
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in the details, the responses I received are linked below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.perplexity.ai/search/select-20-crypto-trading-signa-4Cg4JsODQamvYjYRJ4jvZA&quot;&gt;Perplexity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://chatgpt.com/s/dr_682c09b8f95c8191820593c24b43bc10&quot;&gt;ChatGPT&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the results from Deep Research mode – Perplexity turned out to be much faster. Interestingly, both lists were quite similar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;-investigating-signal-groups-the-chosen-few&quot;&gt;🔎 Investigating Signal Groups: The Chosen Few&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below, you’ll find the prompt I used for validation and the list of groups I finally selected:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;binancekillers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;FedRussianInsiders&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;binancesignals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;wolfoftrading&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cryptoinnercircle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;wolfxsignals_free&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;wallstreetqueenofficial&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;learn2tradenews&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;whalepumpgroup23&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;altsignals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cryptosignals0rg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;coincodecap&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;fatpigsignals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;️--again-just-to-be-clear--im-not-recommending-any-of-these-groups-or-believing-in-their-effectiveness-in-fact-their-effectiveness-is-the-topic-of-the-product-im-currently-working-on&quot;&gt;⚠️  Again…. Just to be clear – I’m not recommending any of these groups or believing in their effectiveness. In fact, their “effectiveness” is the topic of the product I’m currently working on.&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
                <link>/blog/how-i-found-trading-signals-groups-to-audit</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/how-i-found-trading-signals-groups-to-audit</guid>
                
                <category>signals auditor</category>
                
                <category>trading signals groups to audit</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>🧭 How I Plan to Deliver My First Milestone: Collecting Signals from Three Popular Trading Groups</title>
                <description>&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/05-planning-infographic.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Collecting Signals from Three Popular Trading Groups - Linear view&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;-why-i-dont-mix-planning-with-implementation&quot;&gt;🧠 Why I Don’t Mix Planning with Implementation&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the planning phase, the most important thing for me is to be critical of my own ideas. I try to clearly define what’s truly necessary and what can wait. The goal isn’t perfection — it’s to plan actions that are &lt;em&gt;realistic&lt;/em&gt; to deliver in a realistic timeline. This is not the moment for excitement — it’s a time for clear thinking and an honest assessment of what really needs to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I move to the implementation phase, I no longer analyze the decisions I’ve already made. &lt;strong&gt;I deeply trust myself from the time I planned the task&lt;/strong&gt;. Thanks to this, I can focus all my energy on execution without constantly questioning the direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;️-what-am-i-building-now&quot;&gt;🛠️ What am I building now?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal at this stage is to collect trading signals from three sources. First, I need to choose these sources, then write scripts to handle them, store the data in a database, and finally — set up some initial automation for the whole process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;thats-why-ive-prepared-a-specific-task-list-that-will-lead-me-to-this-goal&quot;&gt;That’s why I’ve prepared a specific task list that will lead me to this goal.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/05-planning-linear.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Collecting Signals from Three Popular Trading Groups - Linear view&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Collect a list of signal sources (free and paid) with their types (TG/Discord/etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prepare a schema for captured signals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Configure data persistence for captured signals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop a script to capture signals from a single source&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Automate signal capturing on a schedule&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Automate capturing signals from a second source&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Automate capturing signals from a third source&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Prepare a list of insights to extract from captured signals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Extract insights from captured signal data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;-what-did-i-discover-during-planning&quot;&gt;💡 What did I discover during planning?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During planning, I noticed something interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though my main goal for the first three milestones (described &lt;a href=&quot;how-i-plan-to-validate-trading-signals-auditor-idea-in-the-real-world&quot;&gt;✅ How I plan to validate Trading Signals Auditor idea in the real world&lt;/a&gt;) is to prepare the groundwork to start sharing results from analyzing trading signal group performance — it turns out that collecting the signals alone already allows me to share initial insights. For example, I can show how many signals each group generates, how that number changes over time, and which tokens appear most frequently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a very valuable stage — I can start sharing this kind of data publicly as part of the process of building Signals Auditor. It might be the first point of contact with potential users and a good way to spark early interest in the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-whats-next&quot;&gt;📌 What’s next?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next steps include:preparing a list of signal groups I want to analyze, and implementing the first technical tasks from the backlog I’ve already planned. I’ll keep sharing progress updates — both here on the blog and through other channels, in the spirit of building in public.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
                <link>/blog/how-i-plan-to-deliver-collecting-signals-from-popular-groups</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/how-i-plan-to-deliver-collecting-signals-from-popular-groups</guid>
                
                <category>signals auditor</category>
                
                <category>planning</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>✅ How I plan to validate Trading Signals Auditor idea in the real world</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;-first-things-first-validating-interest-before-building-it-all&quot;&gt;📢 First Things First: Validating Interest Before Building It All&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-want-to-find-out-if-anyone-is-even-interested-in-it&quot;&gt;I want to find out if anyone is even interested in it&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do that, I want to start marketing the product by publishing interesting insights from analyzing trading signal groups — on Twitter, Reddit, and niche forums.  For this, I need to collect and analyze the trading signals, only then I can start sharing my findings publicly and for free, directing people to my landing page with a waitlist option&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be a challenge for me, but while doing all the above tasks, I need to focus above all on the time required to implement them, avoiding overengineering and aiming for simplicity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;-the-goal-is-to-start-collecting-interested-users-on-the-waitlist-as-soon-as-possible&quot;&gt;🎯 The goal is to start collecting interested users on the waitlist as soon as possible.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That’s why I’ll start by planning the tasks that will get me there.&lt;/strong&gt; I will divide it to milestones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;-what-must-be-the-outcome-of-my-next-actions&quot;&gt;📋 What Must Be the Outcome of My Next Actions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;-collected-trading-signals&quot;&gt;📊 Collected Trading Signals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I will prepare scripts that automatically download and process signals from popular groups sharing free trading signals. These scripts will run locally, and the data will be saved in a SQLite database. Initially, I will focus on the most popular groups and simple solutions to quickly launch the data collection process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;️️-verification-of-the-effectiveness-of-the-collected-signals&quot;&gt;🕵️‍♂️ Verification of the Effectiveness of the Collected Signals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step will be to perform backtesting of the collected signals using historical market data. This way, I will determine how effective the signals were and what potential profit or loss they could have generated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;-readiness-to-let-people-join-the-waitlist-for-the-product&quot;&gt;📨 Readiness to Let People Join the Waitlist for the Product&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will create a simple landing page that briefly presents the product, shows sample visualizations, and includes a blog with conclusions from the analyses. Users will be able to join the waitlist by providing their email to receive updates about the product’s availability and interesting insights from the analyses. This way, I’ll be able to build engagement and keep potential users informed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;️-time-to-build&quot;&gt;🛠️ Time to Build&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, it’s time for implementation. For each of the 3 milestones described above—ultimately leading to the start of product promotion and encouraging sign-ups to the waitlist—I will prepare a more detailed task list and begin the implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
                <link>/blog/how-i-plan-to-validate-trading-signals-auditor-idea-in-the-real-world</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/how-i-plan-to-validate-trading-signals-auditor-idea-in-the-real-world</guid>
                
                <category>signals auditor</category>
                
                <category>product validation</category>
                
                <category>building product</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>📈 Trading Signals Auditor - The First Product Idea I’m Most Excited About</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;️-what-is-signals-auditor-and-what-problem-does-it-solve&quot;&gt;🙅‍♀️ What is Signals Auditor And What Problem Does It Solve?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Signals Auditor is a tool that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;reveals the real performance of investment signals from various sources&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;reduces the risk of wasting money on dishonest signal providers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;helps minimize losses caused by inaccurate signals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;supports conscious decisions about buying signals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;exposes scammy trading signal providers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;verifies signals in a practical way by trading selected signals on a real exchange&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;-who-will-benefit-from-this-product&quot;&gt;🎯 Who Will Benefit From This Product&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The product is targeted at investors of all experience levels who don’t want to get scammed out of their money by paying for or using low-quality signals. Instead, they want to make a conscious and informed decision about whether to use such signals and risk their hard-earned money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;-what-about-the-competition&quot;&gt;🏆 What about the competition?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t found any solutions on the market that truly audit the effectiveness of trading signals. A potential customer can only rely on what the signal groups claim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s exactly where Signals Auditor comes in — independent, transparent, and data-driven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;-business-model-and-costs-behind-the-product&quot;&gt;💰 Business Model and Costs Behind the Product&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Access to the real trading signals results will be paid — a subscription model that also gives users influence over the product’s development by allowing them to suggest and choose new features and groups whose signal sources will be audited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The costs include my time spent on developing the product, small IT infrastructure expenses, and the cost of memberships in paid signal groups that will be audited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;-how-i-want-to-promote-it&quot;&gt;📣 How I Want to Promote It&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build an MVP with a clearly defined scope in the coming days.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask for feedback on Reddit — to check if the product makes sense, especially since part of the functionality is ready and I can share stats on signal group reliability.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a Twitter profile and share analysis results during MVP development, including in trading-related threads.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Post weekly or monthly stats — e.g., for specific tokens — on the blog and in communities where traders gather.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set up a landing page with a “buy” button — really a waitlist sign-up with a potential launch promotion. According to Peter Levels, it’s a good way to validate real interest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;️-what-worries-me-the-most-about-launching-this-product&quot;&gt;⚠️ What Worries Me the Most About Launching This Product&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have two main concerns about this product: I’m wondering if I’ll be able to reach people who are interested in it, and I’m also worried about how the owners of the groups that perform poorly will react — especially since it will be known who is behind the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;-opportunities&quot;&gt;🚀 Opportunities&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to build a product from A to Z, and that alone already gives me satisfaction, so this project is, above all, a personal challenge for me. I plan to act in the spirit of Building in Public, so I will regularly share my progress — maybe I’ll also gather some interest and feedback along the way. And even if it doesn’t work out commercially — I’ll be left with knowledge, experience, a toolbox of tools built during development, and data that — if it’s worth it — I can share publicly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;️-whats-my-next-step&quot;&gt;🛠️ What’s my next step&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the post &lt;a href=&quot;how-will-i-choose-product-to-build&quot;&gt;📋 How I’ll choose what product to build&lt;/a&gt;  I planned to describe all potential products first, but I’ve already decided to start building Signals Auditor. That’s why my next step will be to plan the MVP features, breaking them down into milestones and tasks needed to release the first iteration of the product.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
                <link>/blog/what-is-signals-auditor</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/what-is-signals-auditor</guid>
                
                <category>signals auditor</category>
                
                <category>choosing product to build</category>
                
                <category>building product</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>📋 How I’ll choose what product to build </title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ll divide the process into two main stages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;-creating-a-list-of-ideas-and-initial-selection&quot;&gt;📋 Creating a list of ideas and initial selection&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the recommendation from Peter Levels’ book Make, I’ll focus on problems I’ve personally encountered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first step, I’ll create a rough list of problems and potential product ideas that come to mind. Then I’ll narrow it down to a maximum of three ideas for deeper analysis. The goal is to find something that solves a real problem and has a chance of actually being useful to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I’ll describe these products on my blog and ask for feedback in places where I can find potential users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/02-choosing-product-common-what-i-d-like-and-what-somoene-would-pay.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Overlap between &apos;What I would like to build&apos; and &apos;What someone would pay for&apos; — highlighting the sweet spot as potential product to build&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;-describing-the-three-selected-product-ideas&quot;&gt;📝 Describing the Three Selected Product Ideas&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each product description will include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Name and Description&lt;/strong&gt; – A short summary of the product and the problem it solves. I’ll explain why the problem is important and how solving it could help people.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Target Audience&lt;/strong&gt; – Who will benefit the most from this product.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Competition and Differentiation&lt;/strong&gt; – What similar solutions already exist and how my product will be different or better.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Business Model&lt;/strong&gt; – How I plan to make money from this product and what costs I expect.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marketing Ideas&lt;/strong&gt; – How I could get people interested in the product.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concerns and Challenges&lt;/strong&gt; – What I’m worried about and what might be hard during the process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-main-goal-for-may-2025&quot;&gt;✅ Main Goal for May 2025&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My goal for this month is to clearly describe these ideas using the structure above and define what I can quickly build to test market interest — a scope of work for an MVP. It’s important to check as early as possible if the market really needs the solution, before I invest more time and resources into it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
                <link>/blog/how-will-i-choose-product-to-build</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/how-will-i-choose-product-to-build</guid>
                
                <category>choosing product to build</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>🤔 Why am I going to build a product?</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The list will be sharp and to the point, without any filler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’ll have full decision-making power over what I do and how I do it&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I enjoy pursuing goals I set for myself. After completing a demanding AI course and an algotrading bot project, I’m looking for a new, bigger challenge.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My favorite part of professional work is designing and building systems.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is one of two paths I’ve been considering for years. It seems less risky than the other one—building my own service-based company.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ve always had a few product ideas in mind.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I want to do something beyond working for someone else. The main stage of building my professional career is already behind me.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nothing truly bad will happen if I fail — at worst, I’ll gain valuable experience and learn something.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m inspired by people who have done it, like Troy Hunt and his &lt;a href=&quot;https://haveibeenpwned.com/&quot;&gt;Have I Been Pwned&lt;/a&gt; project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I was inspired by Peter Levels’ book Make, in which he shares his experiences building startups solo.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the future, I’d like to be able to say: “I once built my own product, even though I wasn’t sure it would work out.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’d like to build a personal brand along the lines of “he makes cool stuff.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maybe I’ll even make some money from it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned, this blog entry will also serve as a place I can return to whenever I need a reminder of why I started, especially in moments when motivation runs low.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 02:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
                <link>/blog/why-am-i-going-to-build-a-product</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/why-am-i-going-to-build-a-product</guid>
                
                <category>motivation</category>
                
                <category>building product</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>